# Alexandros Filotheou

I hold a PhD in Robotics and I am qualified with a Master's degree in Control and Robotics. I have 7+ years of hands-on experience with SLAM, localisation, autonomous navigation, Computer Vision, and general integration and problem-solving. These I have acquired in real conditions with real robots as well as in simulation. I have mainly used ROS and ROS 2, but also MATLAB/Octave, all the while under Linux. My primary coding language is C++ and my secondary Python. I enjoy documenting my motivation and contributions in a clear and concise manner that acknowledges my audience's existing knowledge with regard to code, presentations, technical papers, or tutorials.

## Work Experience

2023.09 — present	Postdoctoral Research Associate Center for Research and Technology Hellas (CERTH), Thessaloniki, Greece
2018.09 - 2023.03	Research Engineer for NSRF projects Aristotle University of Thessaloniki, Greece
2016.09 - 2016.11	<b>Teaching Assistant</b> · DD2380 Artificial Intelligence KTH Royal Institute of Technology, Stockholm, Sweden
2011.10 - 2012.03 $2011.03 - 2011.05$ $2008.07 - 2009.06$	$ \begin{array}{c} \textbf{Database Designer} \cdot \text{Egnatia Motorway S.A., Thessaloniki, Greece} \\ \textbf{Application Developer} \ (\text{Int}) \cdot \text{Egnatia Motorway S.A., Thessaloniki, Greece} \\ \textbf{Telecommunications Engineer} \cdot \text{OTE Group, Thessaloniki, Greece} \\ \end{array} $

## Voluntary Experience

2013.10 – 2014.07 **Computer Vision Engineer**, PANDORA Robotics Team, Dept. of Electrical and Computer Engineering, Aristotle University of Thessaloniki

#### Education

2018.09 - 2023.06	Doctorate Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering Aristotle University of Thessaloniki, Greece
2015.09 - 2017.06	Master of Science · Systems, Control, and Robotics School of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science KTH Royal Institute of Technology, Stockholm, Sweden
2005.09 - 2013.07	Diploma Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering Aristotle University of Thessaloniki, Greece

#### Computer Skills

Languages C/C++, Python, shell, MATLAB/Octave, {PL/}SQL {Meta-}Operating Systems Linux, ROS 2, ROS
Tools git, OpenCV, Docker, Qt (cpp) | Tkinter (py)
Oracle Forms / Reports, LATEX

#### Languages

English Fluent — IELTS Score 8.5 Greek Native

Thessaloniki, Greece; July 2024 contact: (+30) 693 87 87 677 | alexandros.filotheou@gmail.com source: https://github.com/li9i/cv

### Links

```
Indicative publications: [1] [2] [3] — google scholar

Indicative software packages: cbgl·fsm-lo·lama-odom·pvhd — github

Demos / videos: cbgl·fsm·cultureid·relief·mpc

Portfolio
```

# References

Dr. Antonis Dimitriou · Coordinator of the projects for which I worked during my A.U.Th. years (+30) 697 88 96 350 | antodimi@auth.gr